Kanagawa Prefectural Satozakura High School
Movie Club
Who will be the one to scream!?
Super Scary Movie 7
What? The Super Scary Movie series went up to 5?
Up to 7, actually.
For real?
The seventh one must be really out there.
It became a completely different thing by 7.
It's not even a parody movie anymore.
Then what kind of movie is it?
Convoluted sitcom plus
lineage horror, I suppose?
What the heck?
By a total fluke, and the grandchild of
the main character from 1 ends up living
in a shared house with the
grandchild of the culprit from 2
and the grandchild of the
first person who died in 3,
but it turns out it's a haunted house,
so they call in a spirit medium.
That's the story.
Sounds boring.
It bored me to death.
Who'd watch something like that?
What's interesting, though,
is that the guy from 5 and 6—
Huh?
What are you doing here?
Didn't I tell you not to use this room
because we're making it our club room now?
B-But you haven't been using it lately,
so I thought it was fine now.
So?
So, well, um...
Just get out of here already,
you cockroaches!
L-Let's go, Yoshino.
Next time you use it, we'll send you flying!
Oh, score!
Hey, what are you doing?!
What?
I'm taking it home.
Huh?
Move your foot.
Hey, stop it...
I'm taking this home.
So could you move your foot?
Shit!
Close the door.
Roger.
Movie Club
JUJUTSU KAISEN
Episode 10: Idle Transfiguration
I wonder if the first person to say
"the opposite of fondness is indifference"
went to hell like they should have.
It's just not possible that interacting
maliciously with others
could be more proper than leaving them alone.
"The opposite of fondness is hate."
Japanese people love that.
They like to gloat over
complicating a simple answer.
The man who coined that
phrase wasn't Japanese.
I'm talking about the mistaken translation.
The original phrase,
spoken by some foreigner,
was "the opposite of love
is indifference," right?
There are various definitions of "love,"
so "indifference" works as an antonym there.
That's true.
But we generally don't use
"love" very much, right?
That's why, in this country,
it got changed to "fondness" at some point.
That version spread without any thought
as to whether the opposing definitions
of "love" and "indifference" still held true.
Everyone likes a little wordplay.
After all, humans can't live
without making up excuses.
What's this?
An experiment to see just how
large I can make a single human.
On that one, I tried to see
how small I could make one.
This is...
a human?
Are you used to corpses, Junpei?
I don't know.
If this was my mother, I might lose control
and end up hating you.
But I already know how
repulsive humans can be.
That's why I don't expect
anything from other people,
nor do I think much of it when
someone I don't know dies.
Indifference is the virtue
people ought to strive for.
And despite that, you want revenge.
Are you trying to say that's contradictory?
Do you believe people have hearts?
Huh? Do they not?
They don't.
They have souls,
but souls aren't hearts.
Then what about my—
I'm the only person in this world who
understands the composition of souls.
After all, I change the shape of other
creatures by making contact with them.
All emotions are the result
of the soul's metabolism.
They're far too mechanical to call hearts.
People place too much value
on things they can't see.
I can see them,
and souls are no more special
than physical bodies.
They're just there.
Do you get it?
There's no value or importance to life.
Life just continues its cycle,
same as the waters of the world.
That's true for both you and me.
Our lives are meaningless and have no value.
Li...
And that's why we can do anything we want.
We're free to live our
lives however we please.
You can't let yourself get trapped
in an ideal of indifference.
There's no need for consistency
in how you live your life.
Just as you eat when you get hungry,
you can kill someone if you hate them.
I'll sanction you fully.
There he is.
Huh? Casual clothes?
It looks like he hasn't
attended school for some time.
The same could be said for me, though.
So are the others doing well?
Tuna, tuna!
I hear they're doing quite well.
So what do we do?
We use that.
Huh? Is that a cursed spirit?
It's a fly head,
a low-level curse that doesn't
even qualify as grade 4.
Once we reach a place with no people,
we'll have it attack him.
Huh?!
One: if he's a normal person
who can't perceive curses,
please save him.
Two: if he can perceive it,
but has no means to deal with it,
likewise, please save him.
Then we'll question him
about the day of the incident.
Three: If he exorcises
the fly head with jujutsu...
we immediately restrain him.
By force?
By force.
If it's a misunderstanding, that's fine.
We'll apologize after the fact.
However...
Four: if Yoshino Junpei possesses potential
equal to or greater than a grade 2 sorcerer,
we retreat and meet back up with Nanami-san.
I think I can just barely handle a grade 2.
If this were a cursed spirit, yes.
Huh?
Fushiguro-kun mentioned
it before, remember?
Typically, cursed spirits are assigned
to sorcerers of equal grade.
Sorcerer
Special
One
Two
Three
Four
Cursed Spirit
Special
One
Two
Three
Four
Strong
Weak
That means a grade 2 sorcerer would be
expected to beat grade 2 cursed spirits.
So a grade 2 sorcerer possesses strength
close to a grade 1 cursed spirit.
Why wasn't I ever told
something that important?
Because Gojou-san's so irresponsible...
We'll get out of the car here.
This feels like I'm doing all the work,
and I'm really not into it.
If you plan to come out,
please hurry up and do so.
They may be disfigured and beyond saving,
but murdering people makes me sick.
Ah, what a relief.
I'd be in trouble if Gojou Satoru were here,
but it's not much of an
experiment if you're too weak.
I hate overtime, so let's just...
finish this quickly.
JUJUTSU KAISEN
I'll murder you!
They're similar.
That picture-perfect frivolity,
and the sinister strength behind it.
I did block it, didn't I?
With cursed energy.
Is it that kind of technique?
What do you mean, "that kind"?
I hate abstract questions that
leave interpretation up to others.
That's good.
So you don't hate chatting, then.
It depends on the person.
This cursed spirit is capable
of conversing quite well,
just like the two unregistered
special-grades in Gojou-san's report.
I suppose it would be unnatural
for them to be unrelated.
Hey, tell me.
Which do you think came first,
the soul or the body?
Come on, you know.
It's like the question of whether
the chicken or the egg came first.
Do you think the soul resides in the body?
Or do you think the body
forms around the soul?
I have to listen, I guess...
The former.
Bzzt! The answer is the latter.
The soul always exists before the body.
The shape of the body is pulled
along by the shape of the soul.
I'm not healing.
I'm just strongly maintaining
the shape of my own soul.
You understand now, don't you?
My technique is to make contact
with the soul and alter its shape.
Idle Transfiguration.
I keep a stockpile of humans.
It's rather difficult, though.
Normal people eventually die
when their shape is transfigured.
But what about jujutsu sorcerers?
It's 5:30 PM.
I started work at 10 AM today,
so I'm getting off at 6 PM,
no matter what it takes.
Yoshino.
Where were you?
You know you shouldn't be skipping school.
Sotomura-sensei.
Did you hear?
Apparently Sayama, Nishimura,
and Honda are dead.
You were friends with them, weren't you?
They spent a lot of time with you
when you had no other friends, right?
Yet you didn't even attend their funerals...
Honestly, what's wrong with you?
Friends?
You should go light some incense
for them. I'll even go with you.
Me... and them?
He's insane.
Come on.
You teachers...
You graduate from school
and then go work in schools,
so you don't actually experience
the real world, do you?
That's how we end up with
overgrown children like you, isn't it?
Here, say "ahh."
Every last one of them!
Look over here!
I'll sanction you fully.
What are you mumbling about?
Did you lose your mind from
self-isolation? Just kidding.
Stop!
Oh, this guy...
can see it.
Ow!
Damn, that hurt!
Five
Seconds
Before
the
Operation
Glance.
Here we go, Itadori-kun!
Time out! There's someone there!
Huh?
Oh, no!
Thank goodness.
What? You a gymnast or something?
Hey, I have some things
I want to ask you about.
Would you come with me?
Come on.
That button...
Hold on.
He and I were just talking.
You're rude!
Uh, well, it's a rather important matter.
An important matter?
You're just a kid! What's so important?
And what uniform is tha—
Plop!
What are you doing, you brat?!
Stop! Stop this!
Don't run off with them!
W-Wait!
What was that about?
Okay, now, let's go!
Huh?! That was fast!
You already ran that entire lap?!
Yeah.
You didn't have to go through all that.
You could've just dragged me away.
Well, sure.
But you hate that guy, don't you?
How do you...
Just a hunch.
Oh, was I wrong?
You're not wrong.
You don't want someone you hate loitering
in front of your home forever, right?
Let's head over there for now.
Sure.
Your mobility is impressive.
This is so fun!
So the person's original mass is irrelevant
when it comes to changing their shape?
Either way, it's a bad
match-up for my technique.
...elp me!
Help... me!
You can't save anyone
once they've been reshaped.
If they attack, kill them without hesitation.
That's better for the victims, too.
Oh, sorry.
I've practiced a lot,
so they don't die right away
when I change their size,
but their... brains? Awareness?
I still lack precision with that,
so sometimes their souls sweat like that.
Don't worry about it. Let's continue.
I'm not worried about it.
It's my policy not to bring
personal feelings into work.
You suck at lying!
Your soul is trembling.
So you're... what grade?
Grade 1.
No wonder you're strong.
You'll make the best test subject.
Luck's really on my side.
I'm grateful.
Surprised my speed suddenly increased?
I can alter the shape of my own soul, too.
Jujutsu sorcerers can protect
their bodies with cursed energy,
but they aren't protecting their souls.
For starters, you have to
be aware of your own soul.
It's not possible to protect
it if you can't do that.
But it looks like you subconsciously covered
your soul somewhat with cursed energy.
If you hadn't, you'd already
be under my control.
Although, once I touch you two or three
more times, you'll cease to be human.
I'm not letting you go!
Was that it, grade 1 sorcerer?
You did well running around,
but you're at your limit, aren't you?
Unfortunately...
What?
His cursed energy's increasing?
I'm going into overtime now.
Juju Stroll
Fushiguro!
Have you seen my uniform jacket?
No, I haven't.
That's weird.
I left it right here...
Oh, Panda-senpai. Have you seen my uniform?
I haven't seen it.
Really?
I wonder where it could have gone.
Hey, my skirt's not here, either.
That's a line that can't be crossed.
Mustard leaf!
Bonito flakes!
Jeez, you're both trash.
This image is crazy.
Huh?
This is Maki-san's.
Heya!
I'm Kugisaki Nobara!
Episode 11:
Narrow-minded